《西西里舞曲》
弗雷作曲
丽贝卡·博伊斯
-霍华德  -早上好
- Howard. - Morning!
有麦吉尔的东西
Delivery for McGill.
你来这儿干什么
What're you doing here?
咱俩有一阵没见了
Ah, it's been a while.
我觉得我应该过来看看你
Thought I should come in and check on you.
我刚才好像听到音乐了
Did I hear music?
没  我刚才在...  我帮你拿吧
No, no. I was just -- ‭let me get that for you.
-见到你真好  霍华德  -我也很高兴
- Good to see you, Howard. - Oh, likewise.
大家都非常想你  朋友
You are sorely missed, my friend.
别把这当负担
Don't take that as any undue pressure.
我在考虑  下星期过去待一两个小时
Um, I'm thinking of maybe coming in for an hour or two next week.
随机应变就行
Maybe kind of play it by ear.
如果你愿意的话
Well, ‭i-if you feel comfortable.
我们当然很欢迎你
I mean, we certainly would love to have you.
我们什么都能接受
We will take anything we can get.
日子定了我让欧内斯托提前通知你们一声
I'll figure out a day and get Ernesto to give you a heads up.
不错
That sounds great.
欧尼近来如何
How's Ernie working out?
大体上说  还不错
Uh, he's been fine, for the most part.
太棒了
Excellent.
矶鹞渡一案  一切正常吗
Everything on track with, uh, Sandpiper?
正在进行
Moving along.
戴维斯梅因律所真的很尽力
Davis & Main are, uh... really pulling their weight.
他们最好尽力
Well, they better.
案子很复杂
It's a complex case.
这案子肯定不是两个人就能搞定的
Well, it's definitely not a two-man job, that's for sure.
谁有吉米的消息吗
Anyone, uh, heard from Jimmy?
我有  我跟他谈过
I have, yes. I've talked to him.
他怎么样
How is he?
他很好
He's fine.
还不错
Doing well.
说到他  我有些消息
Speaking of which... I have some news.
他在戴维斯梅因律所工作
He's working at Davis & Main.
做什么
Doing what?
是做律师啊
Oh, working as an attorney.
克利福德·梅因雇了吉米
Clifford Main hired Jimmy?
说实话  他也有疑虑
To be fair, he had his doubts,
但他给了吉米一个机会
but he's giving Jimmy a chance.
他派自己的手下去跟客户联系
He had his own people doing client outreach,
但他们每次和矶鹞渡的住户谈话
but every time they would talk to a Sandpiper resident,
住户就会让吉米出马
Jimmy's name would come up.
你知道的  他
You know, he...
-那些老人  他们  -他们喜欢他
- Those old folks, they just -- - They love him.
的确是
Yeah, they do.
另外  我猜克利福德希望
Plus, I guess Cliff thought it would be a good idea
案子有那种...
for the case to have that sort of, uh...
连续性
you know... continuity.
吉米待人处事有一套
Jimmy certainly has a way with people.
是啊
He does.
戴维斯梅因律所知道他的背景吗
They're aware of his background at Davis & Main?
他的教育情况
His education?
不瞒你说
In the spirit of full disclosure,
克利福徳之前确实跟我谈过
Cliff did talk to me beforehand.
我都实话跟他说了
I didn't pull any punches.
我尽可能客观地跟他说
I tried to paint a complete picture.
但我没有碍事
But I didn't stand in the way.
当然了
Of course not.
你也不应该碍事
Nor should you.
说实话
Truth be told...
金·韦克斯勒为此事极力争取
Kim Wexler pushed for this -- hard.
但我没碍事
But I didn't, uh, you know, stand in the way.
合伙人机会
Partner track?
我会
I would, uh...
对
Yeah.
我想是吧
Assume so.
真不错
That's great.
吉米不错啊
Good for Jimmy.
-骗子查理  对吗  -对
- Charlie Hustle, right? - Yep.
对
‭Yep.
那我不打扰你了
Well, I'll get out of your hair.
还需要我往欧尼的单子上加点别的吗
Anything else you need me to add to Ernie's list?
不用  都有了
No. All set. All good.
谢谢你过来  霍华德
Thanks for coming by, Howard.
不用谢  我们真的很想你
Any time. You truly are missed.
别有压力
No pressure.
绝命律师
第二季 第二集
金柏莉·韦克斯勒
法兰西斯·雪夫
詹姆斯·麦吉尔
文件审查由哈姆林麦吉尔联合律所负责协调
Document review will be coordinated through HHM.
目前  已经向矶鹞渡请求获取以下文件
To date, the following documents have been requested from Sandpiper
作为首次披露申请书的一部分
as part of our initial discovery petition.
一  矶鹞渡所有分部迄今为止的
One -- resident lease agreements, past and present,
居住者租赁协议
from all Sandpiper locations.
二  矶鹞渡全部供应商的
Two -- invoices and transaction documents
发票和交易凭证
from all supply companies used by Sandpiper.
三  矶鹞渡迄今为止所有正式卖主的名单
Three -- list of all past and present official Sandpiper vendors.
四  矶鹞渡与经销商的
Four -- any and all business agreements and contracts
全部业务协议和合同
between Sandpiper and its distributors.
五  居住者社保收据记录
Five -- records of residents' social security check receipts.
六  津贴交易结算清单
Six -- allowance transaction statements.
七  居住者的无关发票...
Seven -- resident invoices non-related to sup--
我喜欢你的新造型
I'm loving the new look.
圣达菲怎么样
How's Santa Fe?
真...
It's, uh --
真的还...
It's -- it's really...
看  我跟你说了
See? What'd I tell you?
地方不错吧
Nice place? ‭
算是公司临租房中最好的吧
The finest in temporary corporate housing.
迫不及待想看了
Can't wait to see it.
也许我该离开哈姆林麦吉尔联合律所
Maybe I should leave HHM.
登上戴维斯梅因的赚钱快车
Get on that cushy D&M train.
赚得又多又快
It is very cushy.
棒极了
It's amazing.
吉米...
Jimmy...
我很为你高兴
I'm so happy for you.
谢谢
Thanks.
情况大有好转
You know, things are really turning around.
我甚至考虑
I'm even thinking of looking, you know,
买自己的房子
my own place to buy.
-在圣达菲吗  -还不确定
- In Santa Fe? - ‭Not sure yet.
也许是离阿尔布开克更近的地方
Maybe someplace, uh, closer to Albuquerque
因为我得经常两头跑
since I'm going between the two so much.
好吧
Okay.
那就两地中间咯
So, halfway points.
我在想...
Yeah, I was thinking, uh...
-等等  科拉莱斯怎么样  -科拉莱斯
- Oh, wait, what about Corrales? - Corrales.
找个精致的小别墅
Yeah, get a nice, little bungalow,
大点也行
or maybe not so little.
平面设计宽敞开阔
Big, open floor plan.
我不希望墙壁扰乱我的气  没错
I don't want any walls disrupting my chi, yeah.
我确实觉得要块大地皮
Uh, but I'm thinking I definitely want some decent acreage,
接触大自然
get in touch with nature.
马
Horses.
没错  你可以养马
Come on. You could get horses.
天  简单太棒了
Man, that would be so amazing.
太贵了  只吃燕麦  对吧
Too expensive. ‭They, uh, all the oats -- right?
它们都吃燕麦吧
It's oats ‭that they're always eating?
-很值  -还有马蹄铁
- It's worth it. - ‭And the horseshoes.
你得给它们用锤子装备好"鞋"
You have to get them shoes and nail them with a hammer.
非常值...
It's totally worth it. It's --
在乡间骑马散步
Long ride through the country
后院一杯酒  看夕阳西下
and then glass of wine on the back patio at sunset.
我们该买个烤肉机
Oh, we should get one of those smokers.
轻轻松松烤几天肉
We could just barbecue for days.
没错  我们真该买一个
Yeah. We definitely got to get a smoker.
好吧...
All right, well...
我得去美甲店了
I got to go to the salon.
他们要运来我崭新的公司用车
They're delivering my new company car.
真的吗
Ugh, are you serious?
怎么
What? ‭
吉夫斯  我的纯金飞艇在哪儿
Jeeves, ‭where's my solid-gold blimp?
小说人物  指理想聪明的男仆
不  不是那辆  另一辆
No, not that one. The other one.
嫉妒
Jealous.
好嫉妒哦
Totally.
我忘了  我给你买了个礼物  等会儿
Oh, I forgot. ‭I got you a present. One sec.
包装真精美
‭Such a beautiful wrapping job.
都不忍打开
It's a shame to open it.
这是礼物  别嘴欠
It's a gift. Be grateful.
世上第二棒的律师
保持真我
Just keeping it real.
别气馁
Come on.
第二已经非常棒了
Second is still very, very good.
好吧
All right.
谢谢
Thanks.
今晚见吗
See you tonight?
再说
Maybe.
如果你表现好的话
If you play your cards right.
你好啊美女
Hello, beautiful.
女士们  喜欢吗
What do you think, ladies?
我知道  很棒吧
Yeah, I know, right?
内部全真皮
It's got all leather interior,
加热座椅适合沙漠地区寒冷的早晨
heated seats for those cold desert mornings.
这绝对是天堂的样子
This must be what heaven looks like.
来个告别拥抱吧
Goodbye hug?
不来吗
No?
好吧  那就擦干泪水
All right, well, forgo the tears
轻轻说一句  后会有期
and just say, "Till we meet again."
大概是公制尺寸的吧
Must be metric.
沃尔多峡谷路
拉谢内加
圣达菲
你在这干什么
What -- what are you doing here?
我在这儿工作
I work here.
真巧啊
Small world.
那这里是警局的停车场吗
So, is this the parking lot for the police station?
是的
It is.
你不知道他们能不能让我进  对吧
You don't know if they validate, do you?
不如你在那边停车吧
Why don't you pull around over there,
我们谈几句
and we'll have a little talk.
好吧
Uh, okay.
你来这干什么
Why are you here?
我有事找警察
I-I have business with the police.
是什么事呢
And what business might that be?
如果你非要知道的话  我被抢劫了
Well, if you must know, I was robbed.
有人闯进我家  偷走了我的财产
Somebody broke into my house and stole my property.
你的毒品吧
Your drugs.
是的  但显然我没对警察说
Yeah, but obviously I didn't tell the cops that.
我又不蠢
I'm not stupid.
你已经和他们说过情况了吗
You've already spoken to them?
两个警察来过我家
A couple of them came by my house.
但我在意的不是毒品
But it's not the drugs that I care about.
不  我在意
I mean, I care.
但我更想讨回我的棒球卡片
It's my baseball cards I need back.
-你的棒球卡片  -是的
- Your baseball cards? ‭- Yes.
我有一套非常珍贵的棒球卡片集
I have a very valuable collection of baseball cards,
被人偷走了
and someone stole them.
我就知道还得我来跟你说
I guess I shouldn't be surprised I have to tell you this.
你已经是个罪犯了  还主动找警察谈话
But it's probably a bad idea that you willingly talk to the police,
这大概不是个好主意
being a criminal and all.
我又不是以罪犯的身份来的
I'm not here as a criminal.
我是受害者
I'm here as a crime victim.
我只是偶尔卖卖药品
Just because I occasionally sell some pharmaceuticals,
就要失去受法律保护的权利吗
I no longer have a right to protection from crime?
而且我和他们谈的时候非常谨慎
And I was very careful when I talked to them.
他们不知道我卖药
I -- they have no idea about my other business.
既然你已经报告过情况了  为什么还要来
If you already made your report, why are you here?
他们喊我来的
They called me.
说还有几个问题要问
They have a few more questions.
他们很努力地在寻找小偷
They are very dedicated to finding this thief.
既然你还是个新手  我来给你解释一下
Since you're new to this, let me explain it to you.
他们在钓鱼
They've invited you on a fishing trip.
什么意思  钓鱼
What's that? A fishing trip?
那些警察对讨回你的卡片根本没兴趣
Those cops have no interest in helping you get your cards back.
他们显然怀疑你
You're obviously under suspicion.
他们什么也没看到啊
There was nothing there for them to see.
你想想我们之前的谈话
I refer you ‭to our previous conversation
再看看这个如霓虹灯般闪闪发光的
and this blinking neon sign of a vehicle
写满"毒贩子"三个字的车
that says "Drug dealer."
他们怀疑你
They suspect you.
他们会让你进去  装作是你的朋友
They will get you in there, pretend to be your friend,
给你一种虚假的安全感
lull you into a false sense of security,
然后他们会让你心虚
and then they will sweat you.
你就会露出破绽
and you will break.
我不  我
I don't -- I --
我不同意
I disagree.
没有商量的余地  你现在就回家
Not open for debate. You go home now.
但是我和他们约好了啊
But I have an appointment.
爽约
Break it.
如果他们打电话给你  别接
And if they call you, do not answer the phone.
那我的棒球卡片怎么办
But what about my baseball cards?
那是你生意的代价
Cost of doing business.
不行  不不不
No! No, no, no!
我得讨回来
I am getting those back!
我愿意冒险
I will take the risk!
不  你不能冒险
No, you won't.
因为你会把我也置于险境
Because then you'll be putting my well-being at risk.
我只能这样
I have to!
我  我
I-I --
那些卡片啊
Those cards?
有一部分是我爸留给我的
Some of them were my dad's.
我要讨回来
I-I am getting them back.
我必须讨回来
I'm getting them back.
我会找到你的卡片的
I'll find your cards.
先生  你
Is -- sir--
你也能做这个吗
Is that something you do?
那真是
Wow, that's...
那你真是太好了
That is so generous of you.
你要付我钱的
Oh, it'll cost you.
好吧
Okay, uh...
我们可以讨论下财务问题
We should discuss some sort of financial arrangement
我可以...
in which I-I, uh...
那好吧
Okay, then!
老天
Jesus.
戴维斯梅因律所
律师
保证金
矶鹞渡生活协助中心
居住合同
请进
Come on in.
我不是故意打断你的
I didn't mean to interrupt.
没关系  我只是弹琴放松一下
Not at all. I was just blowing off some steam.
-弹得挺不错  -谢谢
- You sound good. - ‭Thank you.
有助于保持头脑清醒  你会弹吗
Clears the head. You play?
上高中时学过一阵
Oh, I tried to learn in high school,
但后来我决定用更简单的方法追女孩
but then I decided there were easier ways to get girls.
我希望你有减压的方法
well, I hope you've got a way to decompress.
人人都需要减压
Everybody needs something.
你在这适应得怎么样
How you settling in?
挺好的
Great.
对我来说是向前迈了一大步
Uh, it's -- ‭it's quite a step up for me.
我们很高兴有你加入
Well, we're happy to have you.
有其他需要随时告诉我们  吉米
Just let us know if there's anything else you need, Jimmy.
谢谢  克利福德
Thanks...Cliff.
我也很高兴能加入这里
Um, I'm happy to be here.
很好
Great.
我该回去工作了
Uh, better get back to it.
好的  我也该工作了
Yeah, me, too, I suppose.
其实  我在首次信息披露中发现了点东西
Actually, um, ‭I might have found something in the initial disclosures.
-是吗  -斯韦卡特和考科利不断提到
- Oh, yeah? - Schweikart and Cokely keep referring to
这是一个"可选的津贴项目"
the "Optional Allowance Program,"
但是我查了很多住户的合同
but I checked a number of residents' contracts.
所有合同都选择了这个津贴计划
Not a single one has opted out, which makes me think
我认为这更像是一个强制性的财务安排
it's more of a mandatory financial arrangement.
你认为这就是他们在提交的材料中所指的
And you're thinking that's the "Failure to state a claim"
"起诉理由不足"吗
that they filed in their answer?
他们不断强调这是可选计划  是自愿的
They keep saying it's optional, thereby voluntary.
我们可以反驳他们
I think we can counter that
如果入住的前提条件是必须"选择加入"
if "Opting in" is a requirement for residency,
事实也是如此
which it sure seems to be,
那他们声称的"自愿"就站不住脚了
well, their voluntary claims don't hold water.
你这个发现可能意义重大
Might be on to something here.
干得漂亮  吉米
Nice work, Jimmy.
谢谢  克利福德
Thanks, Cliff.
你好
Hola.
你好啊
Hola. Cómo estás?
欢迎光临  有什么能为您效劳的
Welcome. How can I help you?
我想打听下价钱
Um, I was hoping to get an estimate.
是我的车
Uh, mi car. Mi coche.
你们可以干车子的活吧
You do cars?
当然可以  没问题
Sí. Cars. Todo el tiempo.
我想把坐椅的椅面换一下
I-I was hoping ‭to get my seats reupholstered.
跟我出去看一下好吗
Um, take a look? Mira?
-稍等一下  -好的
- Un momento. - ‭Sí, sí, sí, sí.
谢谢
Gracias.
就是这辆
Yeah.
换点新鲜东西
Thinking something new.
给这个老家伙一点宠爱
Give the old girl a little love.
我很高兴干这个活儿
但是有这些钱还不如买辆新车
他说你还是留着钱买辆新车比较划算
He said you should save your money and get a new car.
是吗  但是我对这辆车有特殊的感情
Yeah? Well, it has a sentimental value.
古董车
Classic car.
他想要什么样的
椅面想用什么材料
What material do you want?
当然是皮的
Well, I was thinking leather, definitely.
鳄鱼皮就不错
Maybe alligator.
那要花好多钱呢
Señor. Too much money.
是  但我说了  我对这车有感情
Yeah, but like I said, it has a sentimental value.
我觉得奇奇怪怪的皮革跟这车不太配
换点跟车的风格更搭的材料比较好
说服他
他说鳄鱼皮跟这辆车不搭
He says, uh, alligator's gonna look all wrong.
便宜点的材料更好
Cheaper might be better.
给我看看你选的
Well, show me what you'd pick.
抱歉  先生
I'm sorry, señor.
我儿子  让他来帮你  行吗
My son -- ‭he -- he will help you, okay?
帮他选个材料
别给他推销贵的了
见到你很高兴
Mucho gusto.
你怎么找到我的
How'd you find me?
你找我干什么
Why are you here?
棒球卡
Baseball cards.
我猜  你看到那个开豪车的中年危机男
The way I figure, you saw that mid-life crisis of a vehicle
就明智地决定不和他做生意了
and wisely decided ‭to cut ties with the man,
这我不怪你  因为我也不和他做了
and I don't blame you -- I did, too.
但是你劫了他家
And then you ripped him off.
我相信顺走那些棒球卡
And I'm sure those baseball cards
还能从那个蠢货身上额外捞一笔
looked like an easy way to make a few extra bucks
顺便还能给他上一课
off that idiot, teach him a lesson, too.
但是你低估了
But you underestimated
这个人有多么白痴
just how big an idiot you were dealing with.
不  我很清楚
No, I am pretty aware.
好吧  那么你低估了
Well, then, you underestimated
这个人对这些棒球卡片的感情有多深
how attached the man was to those cards --
深到他打给警察报失
so attached he called the police and reported them stolen.
现在警察在到处查
Now they're nosing around.
这好像是你的问题
That sounds like a "you" problem.
不  我觉得更像是我们的问题
No, I think it's very much an "us" problem.
我想我还是碰碰运气吧
Yeah, I guess I'll just have to take my chances.
不过祝你好运
But good luck to you.
我还希望你能看到我们的困境
You know, I was hoping you'd see our dilemma
做出正确的选择
and do the right thing.
但我想现在是一个软硬兼施的情况
But I think what we have here now is a carrot-and-stick situation.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
这是要来硬的吗
This is the stick? Hmm?
你来威胁我的家人吗
You coming here, threatening my family?
你得再强硬些  老东西
'Cause you're gonna need a bigger stick, old man.
我不是要威胁你的家人
I'm not here to threaten your family.
真正的狠角色是屠库·塞拉曼加
And the name of the stick is Tuco Salamanca.
如果你不照我说的做  恕我直言
Now, you don't play ball, so to speak,
屠库要是发现了你的第二职业
and Tuco finds out about your little side business.
这够硬了吗
That a big enough stick?
不过  我还是更喜欢软的
However, I prefer the carrot.
我觉得你也会喜欢
I think you will, too.
那要怎么做
And what would that be?
你把棒球卡片还给我
You give me back the baseball cards,
还有一万美金现钞
$10,000 in cash,
你还可以净赚大约
and you net roughly --
大约六万美金
roughly -- $60,000.
那该怎么做
And how exactly does that work?
欧内斯托
Ernesto.
要出门吗
Going somewhere?
是的
Yes, we are.
转弯的时候需要些技巧
She's a little tricky around the corners.
而且  得加高级汽油
So... and you got to go with the premium gas.
我知道这好像是骗人的  但还是有很大不同
I know it seems like a scam, but it makes a huge difference.
我会一周洗一次车
And I would get her washed at least once a week.
还要手工打蜡
And spring for the hand wax.
这透明涂层需要多一层保护
You're gonna want that extra layer of protection for the clear coat.
这车值得最好的保护
She deserves the best.
我会确保拆车厂的伙计们
I'll make sure the boys at the chop shop
对她温柔一些的
are real gentle with her.
等等  为什么要拆
Wait. W-why?
不
No.
你觉得我会开那辆车吗
You think I'd be caught dead driving that thing?
那就跟六岁皮条客的校车一样
It looks like a school bus for 6-year-old pimps.
好了  我们能继续了吗
All right, shall we move this along?
阿伦
Aaron.
好  这是基特那张
Okay, there's Jeter.
好的  好的
All right. Okay.
曼托  曼托  这是曼托那张
Mantle. Mantle. There's Mantle.
完事了吗
‭We good?
是的  好像都在这儿
Uh, yeah, that looks like everyone.
都在  都在这儿了
Yeah, they're here. ‭Looks like everyone's here.
另外一样
And now the other item.
现在我们的交易正式结束
And now our business is concluded.
我一直在想是不是该向你道歉
You know, I can't help thinking an apology was in order.
又是警察打来的
Uh, it's -- it's the police again.
矶鹞渡并没有真正回应我们的披露请求
Sandpiper hasn't really responded to our discovery requests.
他们让我们做了大量文书工作
They've buried us in paperwork,
但没有任何东西跟这个案子的详情有关
but nothing actually relevant to the particulars in this case.
意料之中
No real surprise there.
我们也许该要求他们出示银行记录
We may have to subpoena their bank records.
谢谢  艾琳  吉米
Thank you, Erin. Jimmy.
客户那儿处理的怎么样了
How we doing with client outreach?
我们在等那些传票的同时
Oh, while we're waiting on those subpoenas,
还应该尝试从客户那里
I'm thinking we should try wrangling some of this stuff
获取文件
from the clients themselves.
他们中大部分人都会保留复印文本
Most of these folks have hard copies of everything
可追溯到埃森豪威尔时代
going back to ‭the Eisenhower administration.
当然  考虑到他们的...
Of course, given some of their, uh...
不一致的组织方式
inconsistent organizational practices,
进展会很缓慢
it's gonna be slow going.
抱歉打断一下
I'm so sorry to interrupt.
有一位女士  人很好
Uh, this one lady, um, she's sweet,
但是完全听不见
but, uh, deaf as a doornail.
她把所有的文件都放在  放在
She keeps all of her paperwork in, um, she keeps it --
对不起  抱歉  吉米
I'm sorry. Excuse me, Jimmy.
我需要所有人的手机
I'm gonna need everybody's phone,
钥匙  还有电子设备
key fobs, and electronics.
查克  欢迎
Chuck. Welcome.
请坐
Please. Have a seat.
不要在意我
Don't mind me.
大家好
Hey, everybody.
抱歉打扰了
Sorry for the interruption.
就当我不在这儿
Just pretend I'm not here.
很高兴你能来
Happy to have you.
吉米  我们说到哪儿了
Jimmy, where were we?
对
Uh, yeah.
我正说到...
So, I was saying...
从部分委托人那获取文件
getting the documents from some of the clients...
他们中的有些人显然是囤物狂
We definitely have some pack rats.
祝他们好运
God bless 'em.
我那天去拜访圣达菲矶鹞渡的古斯多夫女士
I was visiting Mrs. Gusdorff at, uh, Sandpiper Santa Fe,
那天下午我都在整理大卖场发放的
and I spent the whole afternoon sorting through just a haystack
成堆的菜谱和半价优惠券
of recipes and half-off coupons from Big Lots.
但整理的成果是这位女士
But now we've got copies of this woman's monthly statements
从1997年3月起的月账单
going back to march 1997,
因此  尽管这样有些耗费人力
so it might be a little labor-intensive,
但委托人永远是我们最好的资源
but our clients will always be our best resource.
此外  他们那还有糖吃
Plus, they have ribbon candy.
吉米
Jimmy.
你好
Hello?
你来干什么
What are you doing here?
我名字就刻在这座楼上
‭My name is on the building.
很高兴你能回来
So great to have you here.
如果你需要什么  我就在办公室
If you need anything, I'll be in my office.
你来干什么
Why are you here?
来亲眼见证
To bear witness.
詹姆斯·麦吉尔
James Mcgill.
我是厄门绍特
It's Ehrmantraut.
你的道德观念还够灵活吗
You still morally flexible?
如果是  我有个活儿给你
If so, I might have a job for you.
何时何地
Where and when?
请坐
Take a seat.
沃莫尔德先生  感谢你能前来配合调查
Mr. Wormald, thank you for coming in and talking to us.
应该的
Yeah, of course.
我们看了警官在现场
Yeah, we've been looking at the reports
所写的报告
that the officers took at the scene,
我们有几个后续的小问题
and we have a few ‭small follow-up questions.
抱歉浪费你的时间  只是常规流程
Sorry to waste your time. Just standard stuff.
没必要带律师过来
There's really no need for a lawyer to be here.
我其实是来当他的顾问
I'm here in more of an advisory capacity.
丹只是想有个友善的人在他身边
Dan just, uh, wanted a friendly face next to him.
我们都很友善啊
‭Well, we're all friendly here.
看看我们  四个朋友
Look at us. Four friends.
我们只是想理清事实
We just want to get the facts straight
以便找回你的财物
so we can, um, help you get your property for you.
其实...没关系的
Yeah, you know, uh, it's fine.
用不着...
Uh, yeah, there's no need to, uh --
不  这只是常规程序
No, it's just standard procedure.
你知道  警官有时
You know, ‭officers don't always get
也无法把所有的所需信息写进报告里
all the information we need in their report.
我们只是想抓住偷了你的棒球卡的人
We just want to find the guys who took your baseball cards.
是啊  那...
Yeah, that's, uh...
我叔叔有一张泰·柯布的烟草卡
You know, my uncle ‭had a Ty Cobb tobacco card.
他把那玩意存放在十五厘米厚的玻璃底下
Kept that thing behind six inches of glass
好像是幅名画一样
like it was the Mona Lisa or something.
泰·柯布
Wow. Ty Cobb?
告诉他把光线调暗
Tell him to keep the lights low.
就算是人工照明也会释放一定量的
Even artificial lighting has a certain amount
紫外辐射  那可能会...
of ultraviolet radiation that can, uh, you know...
长远来看...
over the long term --
你能告诉我们
Um, can you just remind us
你在屋子里存放卡片的准确位置吗
exactly where you kept your cards in the house?
好的  正如我想说的  那不再是问题了
Yeah, well, uh, as I was trying to say, it's no longer an issue.
我找到它们了
I found them.
你找到卡片了
So you found the cards?
是的
Uh, yep.
我就是想亲自过来  告诉你们
I just wanted to come down and tell you, you know, in person.
你找到了
You found them?
在哪  房子周围吗
Where? Around the house?
不是  我雇了私家侦探
No. I, uh, I hired a private investigator,
他找到了卡片
and he tracked them down.
是的
So, yeah.
真的吗  哪儿找到的
Really? So, where were they?
没关系了  真的
You know, it's fine. It is.
我真的...我不能再打扰你们了
I really -- I ought to get out of your hair.
你们在我身上浪费的时间够多了
You've wasted enough time on me.
不  不  没关系  这是我们的工作
No, no, it's -- ‭it's okay. It's our job.
我们只是想弄清真相
We just want to get the facts right
以便帮你结案
so we can help close this case for you.
已经搞定了
It's done.
案子结了
Case closed!
我知道你们有多...
I just -- I know how much, you know,
你们有多少案子需要处理
you guys have on your hands,
杀人犯  抢劫犯  黑帮什么的
like murderers and robbers and gangs and stuff. I --
丹尼  你要不要出去透会气
Hey, Danny, ‭why don't you get some air?
你去喝点咖啡
You can have some coffee.
我来和警探们说清楚
I'll finish up ‭with the detectives here.
好了  伙计们  我们直说吧
Okay, let's get down to brass tacks here, guys.
我猜你们两位制服整齐的警官
I'm guessing your two fine uniformed officers
发现了沃莫尔德先生藏东西的据点
found Mr. Wormald's little hidey hole,
所以你们才如此热心地
and that's why you two are so interested
"帮助"我这位朋友
in "Helping" my friend here.
我明白
I get it.
在踢脚线背后发现藏匿地点
A hiding place in the baseboard --
任何人都会起疑心的
it's gonna make anyone suspicious.
但我保证没有违法的事
But let me assure you there's nothing illegal going on here.
那他为什么这么紧张
Then why is he so nervous?
因为要我说  流汗就值得怀疑
'cause I must say, the flop sweat is kind of suspect.
我们都有秘密  不是吗
We all have our secrets, don't we?
又有谁是一尘不染的呢
And who among us is without sin?
但那些罪过不全是犯罪
But those sins aren't all of the criminal variety,
沃莫尔德先生也没有犯罪
and neither are Mr. Wormald's, okay?
但那是很私密的东西
They are, however, very private.
私密  比如贩毒吗
Private, like drug dealer, maybe?
不  当然不是
No, no!
他一直回避  因为那是个敏感话题
He's being evasive because it's a sensitive subject,
需要小心处理  和执法完全无关
very delicate, and of no concern to law enforcement.
尽管我们想相信你的话
You know, as much as we'd love to, um, take your word for it,
但你说的这些还不够
we're gonna need a little more than that.
好吧  这都归结到一起私人纠纷上
All right, well, this all comes down to a personal dispute.
就这样
That's all.
是沃莫尔德先生
It's -- it's between, um, Mr. Wormald
还有他的艺术赞助人的纠纷
and, uh... his art patron.
-"艺术赞助人"  -没错
- "Art patron"? - ‭Yeah.
我的委托人和一个有钱人有一个协议
Uh, my client has an arrangement with a wealthy gentleman
沃莫尔德先生向他提供
for whom Mr. Wormald provides...
艺术品  以此获得他慷慨的...
art in exchange for ‭this gentleman's generous, uh...
我们称之为资助
We'll call it patronage.
艺术品  例如绘画吗
Art? Like -- like what? Paintings?
更像是电子媒体
It's more like digital media.
电子媒体
Digital media?
他为那个人拍视频
He made videos for the man.
哪种视频
What kind of videos?
具有艺术性的私人视频
Private videos of an artistic nature.
那就是藏在暗道里的东西
That's what was in the hiding place.
就是这样
That's what it's for.
那么这个艺术赞助人偷了视频和棒球卡吗
So, this art patron stole the videos and the baseball cards?
那是个误会
Well, there was a misunderstanding.
还是叫创意分歧比较好
I mean, uh, ‭call it creative differences.
艺术家都是喜怒无常的
Artists are volatile creatures.
伙计们  这就是情人吵架
Guys, this all comes down to just a lovers' spat, okay?
两个成年男子闹翻了
Two consenting adults had a falling out.
常有的事
That happens.
赞助人偷了视频
And the, uh, "Patron" stole the videos
还有棒球卡  我猜是为了"表明观点"
and the baseball cards, uh, to "Make a point," I guess.
但关键是  都解决了
But the headline here is, it's all settled.
感情修复了
Hearts have mended,
沃莫尔德先生不会起诉
and Mr. Wormald will not be pressing charges.
视频内容是什么
What was on these videos?
-很私密  -我知道
- They were private. - You've said that.
视频内容意在
They were videos intended
刺激感官
to titillate the senses.
-好吧  是黄片吗  -不
- Okay, so porn. - Not -- no.
不是这种
Not as such.
严格来说  应该是恋物视频
Technically, they would be categorized as fetish videos.
但没有违法内容
But nothing illegal.
就是一个男人  穿戴整齐  我补充一句
Just a man -- a fully clothed man, I might add --
只有他自己
Just all by himself.
沃莫尔德先生穿戴整齐
Just -- just Mr. Wormald fully clothed,
没错
yeah.
-就是这样  -好的
- So... - All right.
所以穿戴整齐的沃莫尔德先生
So, fully clothed Mr. Wormald
在做什么事
by himself doing what?
是啊  在做什么
Yeah, come on, man. What?
"蹲派"
Squat cobbler.
蹲什么玩意儿
What's a s-squat cobbler?
蹲派  你们知道的
Squat cobbler. ‭You know what squat cobbler is.
不  我不知道那是什么
No, I don't -- I don't know what a squat cobbler is.
我也不知道  那是什么
No, me neither. What is it?
你们两是警察吗
What? And you two guys are cops?
霍博肯蹲派
Hoboken squat cobbler.
满月派
Full moon moon-pie.
波士顿奶油派
Boston cream splat.
真的吗
Seriously?
"蹲男"西蒙
Simple-simon-the-ass-man.
荷兰苹果蹲
Dutch apple ass.
伙计们  我说的不是英语吗
Guys, am I not speaking english here?
蹲派到底是什么
What the hell is a squat cobbler?!
就是一个男人坐在派里
It's when a man sits in pie!
他坐在派里
He sits in a pie!
还来回扭动
And he... he wiggles around.
也许是好乐门蛋黄酱
Maybe it's like Hellmann's mayonnaise.
落基山以西有不同的叫法
It has a different name west of the Rockies.
我也不知道  但严格来说
I don't know. But, uh, technically,
他是边哭边蹲的
He does a crybaby squat, so there's tears,
所以看起来更专业
which makes it more specialized.
不是所有蹲派者都要哭的
Not all pie sitters cry.
但我要说的是
But I'm gonna tell you something.
这家伙一哭起来
This guy is a regular Julianne Moore
演得比朱丽安·摩尔还棒
once he gets ‭the waterworks cranked up.
派
Pies?
比如苹果派吗
What? Like apple?
伙计  不是我拍的好吗
Guys, I'm not ‭the filmmaker here, all right?
有香蕉奶油  桃子
Banana cream. I -- uh, peach.
哦对  还要穿道具服装
Oh, and there -- ‭and there is a costume involved.
你忽悠我们呢
You got to be shitting us.
是啊  随便你们信不信
Yeah, like I would make this up.
大千世界无奇不有  兄弟
Hey, the world is ‭a rich tapestry, my friends.
不过相信我
But trust me on this.
你们不会想看的
You don't want to see it.
所以  没事了  是吧
So, uh, we're good, right?
是  没问题了
Yeah. Great.
不过  还有一个小隐患  要善后
There is, however, one little, tiny hanging chad.
什么  什么隐患
Well, what? What chad?
你得拍一个视频
You're gonna have to make a video.
等等等等
wait. Wait.
他是把馅饼吃了还是坐在馅饼里
So he eats the pies or just sits in them?
都有  想要什么有什么
Both. Whatever you want.
哪个先来
Which comes first?
随便
Uh, it's dealer's choice.
这时候就该上哭戏了  是吧
That's where the crying comes in, right?
哭戏是必须的
That's a safe bet.
你到底是怎么想出这主意的
How the hell ‭did you come up with that?
就是给我一百年
If you gave me a million years,
我也想不出这玩意
I still would not have come up with that.
灵感女神
The muse.
我说出了她的想法
She speaks through me.
我不过是区区传话筒
I am but a humble vessel.
他们信了吗
And they bought it?
信了
Yeah.
我也听说过一些很离谱让人难以相信的情节
I've heard some far-out scenarios used to sow doubt,
但这绝对是最扯淡[赢得蛋糕]的
but this definitely takes the cake.
金  金  金
Kim, Kim, Kim.
-知道啦是"馅饼"  -对
- Takes the pie. ‭- Yeah.
抱歉
Sorry.
我现在应该跳楼谢罪
I should just jump off the roof right now.
对啊  你是该自责
Yeah, you should feel bad about yourself.
天哪  你可真能诌
Jesus, can you tell a story.
我觉得其实是那视频让他们信了
Well, to be fair, I think it was the video that clinched it.
什么视频
What video?
等等  你们真的拍了一个视频
Wait, wait. You -- ‭you actually made a video?
不得不说  到最后  老丹还挺入戏的
I got to say, in the end, Ol' Dan really committed.
那眼泪把我都打动了
I believed the tears.
这个是剩下的道具  多出来的
Um, this is a leftover prop. It was extra.
我不确定我们要拍几条  就多买了些
I wasn't sure how many takes we would need, so I over-bought,
不过我保证  绝对没被屁股坐过
But I promise you, ‭untouched by human buttocks.
你伪造证据
You fabricated evidence?
我就拍了个视频
I made a video.
算不上证据
Not exactly evidence.
你用它来为委托人脱罪
You used it to exonerate a client.
你用伪造的证据为委托人脱罪
You used falsified evidence to exonerate a client.
你这是钻牛角尖
Mm, I think you're splitting hairs.
我没有钻牛角尖
I'm not splitting hairs.
万一戴维斯梅因律所发现你伪造证据怎么办
What if Davis & Main find out you faked evidence?
他不是戴维斯梅因律所的客户
It wasn't a Davis & Main client.
这不是什么案子  无偿的
It was some nothing, little pro-bono thing.
与工作无关  完全是  我的私事
It was off the clock. It was, uh, totally my own thing.
为什么
Why?
你为什么要冒丢工作的风险
Why would you risk the best job you've ever had
就为了一个无偿的案子
for some pro-bono case?
我是帮朋友的忙
I was doing a favor for a friend.
冒着被取消律师资格的风险  真是良友
Risking disbarment? That's -- that's some friend.
没事的  事情解决了
It's fine! It -- it worked out.
戴维斯梅因律所并不知情
Davis & Main are none the wiser.
吉米  你这是在玩火
Jimmy, ‭you're playing with fire here.
那天晚上那个混蛋肯
I didn't see you complaining
帮我们付酒单的时候  我可没见你抱怨
when, um, Ken the douchebag paid our bar bill the other night.
是吧  那也有点违反规定了吧
No, that was a little bit of rule breaking right there.
要是我没记错  你还挺享受的
And if I remember correctly, you liked it.
很享受
A lot.
这完全不是一回事
That is so not the same thing.
怎么不是一回事  有什么区别
How? What's the difference?
那与工作无关
That had nothing to do with work.
而且我们就是在胡闹
And we were just -- just screwing around.
但是这个
This?
伪造证据
Fabricating evidence.
吉米  这真的可能会害了你
Jimmy, ‭this could really hurt you.
如果他们发现了  如果你被抓
If they find out, if you get caught --
这  他们永远不会发现的
It -- they're never gonna find out.
你不是吧
Seriously?
这话说得就跟那些蠢蛋罪犯一模一样
You sound like every dumb criminal out there.
如果你再这么干  他们迟早会发现
If you keep this up, they will find out.
你图什么  吉米
For what, Jimmy? ‭
到底为了什么
What is the point?
你不能再做这种事情了
I cannot hear ‭about this sort of thing.
一次也不行了  听到了吗
Ever again. Okay?
我认真的  吉米
I mean it, Jimmy.
不会再有了
You won't.